<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Change on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/change/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Change on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.144.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why We Struggle to Change (And the Simple Fix That Works)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-real-reason-we-struggle-to-change-and-how-to-fix-it-for-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-real-reason-we-struggle-to-change-and-how-to-fix-it-for-good/</guid>
      <description>Change isn&amp;#39;t about willpower—it&amp;#39;s about identity. Discover why habits fail and how shifting your identity leads to lasting change.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="why-we-struggle-to-change-and-the-simple-fix-that-works"><strong>Why We Struggle to Change (And the Simple Fix That Works)</strong></h1>
<p>I used to think change was about willpower.</p>
<p>If I wanted to exercise more, eat better, focus longer, or wake up earlier, I just had to try harder. Push through resistance. Be disciplined.</p>
<p>I told myself, <em>“Just do it. No excuses.”</em></p>
<p>And for a while, it worked. I’d wake up early, go to the gym, power through tasks, and feel like I was finally winning at life.</p>
<p>But then, inevitably, I’d slip. One skipped workout. One late night. One missed deadline.</p>
<p>And every time I failed, I didn’t just feel unmotivated—I felt stuck. Like I just wasn’t the type of person who could stick to things.</p>
<p>Then I learned something that changed everything:</p>
<p><strong>We don’t fail because we’re lazy. We fail because we rely on willpower instead of identity.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="why"><strong>Why &ldquo;Trying Harder&rdquo; Never Works</strong></h2>
<p>Think about this:</p>
<p>Two people are offered a cigarette.</p>
<ol>
<li>The first person says, <em>“No thanks, I’m trying to quit.”</em></li>
<li>The second person says, <em>“No thanks, I don’t smoke.”</em></li>
</ol>
<p>The first still sees themselves as a smoker fighting temptation. The second has already rewritten their identity.</p>
<ul>
<li>The first person is using willpower—constantly resisting.</li>
<li>The second person doesn’t need willpower because their identity has shifted.</li>
</ul>
<p>That’s why most habits fail.</p>
<p>We focus on changing actions instead of changing who we are.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-identity-based-approach-to-change"><strong>The Identity-Based Approach to Change</strong></h2>
<p>Instead of relying on motivation or discipline, I started shifting my identity first.</p>
<p>Every action we take is a vote for the type of person we want to become.</p>
<ul>
<li>If I show up at the gym, I’m casting votes for becoming a fit person.</li>
<li>If I write consistently, I’m becoming a writer.</li>
<li>If I procrastinate, I’m reinforcing the identity of someone who avoids challenges.</li>
</ul>
<p>I had to stop seeing habits as things I <em>do</em> and start seeing them as things that define who I am.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="how-im-rewiring-my-brain-for-lasting-change"><strong>How I’m Rewiring My Brain for Lasting Change</strong></h2>
<p>I started with small identity shifts:</p>
<ul>
<li>Instead of <em>“I should exercise more,”</em> I tell myself <em>“I’m the kind of person who moves every day.”</em></li>
<li>Instead of <em>“I need to focus better,”</em> I remind myself <em>“I’m someone who works with deep focus.”</em></li>
<li>Instead of <em>“I need to stop procrastinating,”</em> I say <em>“I’m the type of person who takes action immediately.”</em></li>
</ul>
<p>At first, it felt fake. But here’s the key:</p>
<p><strong>The brain hates cognitive dissonance.</strong></p>
<p>When you tell yourself you <em>are</em> something, you subconsciously start acting like it.</p>
<ul>
<li>If I tell myself I’m someone who moves every day, it feels wrong to sit on the couch all day.</li>
<li>If I see myself as a deep worker, it feels unnatural to check my phone every five minutes.</li>
<li>If I’m the type of person who takes action immediately, procrastination feels out of character.</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s not about forcing myself to change. It’s about making the new behavior feel like who I am.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-difference-between-trying-and-being"><strong>The Difference Between Trying and Being</strong></h2>
<p>I used to say:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>“I’m trying to exercise more.”</em></li>
<li><em>“I’m trying to focus better.”</em></li>
<li><em>“I’m trying to wake up earlier.”</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Now I say:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>“I’m a person who moves every day.”</em></li>
<li><em>“I’m someone who works with focus.”</em></li>
<li><em>“I’m the kind of person who gets up early.”</em></li>
</ul>
<p>The first set is about effort. The second set is about identity.</p>
<p>And identity is powerful. It sticks. It changes how you see yourself. And how you see yourself changes your actions.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-takeaway"><strong>The Takeaway</strong></h2>
<p>Willpower is unreliable.<br>
Motivation fades.<br>
But identity sticks.</p>
<p>If you want to change something, don’t start with what you do.<br>
Start with who you are.</p>
<ul>
<li>Want to read more? Become a reader.</li>
<li>Want to be healthier? Become the kind of person who prioritizes health.</li>
<li>Want to write more? Become a writer, even before you’re “good” at it.</li>
</ul>
<p>Because the truth is:</p>
<p><strong>We don’t act consistently with our goals. We act consistently with our identity.</strong></p>
<p>Change who you are, and the actions will follow.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
