<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Problem-Solving on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/problem-solving/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Problem-Solving on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.144.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/problem-solving/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why I, a Programmer, Still Use Paper Like It’s 1999</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-i-a-programmer-still-use-paper-like-its-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-i-a-programmer-still-use-paper-like-its-1999/</guid>
      <description>Digital tools are powerful, but when it comes to problem-solving, nothing beats paper. Here’s why I, a programmer, still use analog methods.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="why-i-a-programmer-still-use-paper-like-its-1999"><strong>Why I, a Programmer, Still Use Paper Like It’s 1999</strong></h1>
<p>I spend my entire day in front of a screen—writing code, debugging, fixing issues. Everything I do is digital.</p>
<p>And yet, whenever I need to <strong>truly think</strong>, whenever I need to <strong>solve a problem</strong>, I reach for something ancient.</p>
<p><strong>Paper.</strong></p>
<p>Yes, real, dead-tree, old-school <strong>paper</strong>. With an <strong>actual pen.</strong> No stylus, no tablet. Just ink and a blank page.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="why-do-i-do-this"><strong>Why Do I Do This?</strong></h2>
<p>People at my last job called me old-school. Some thought I was joking.</p>
<p><em>&ldquo;You’re a programmer, why aren’t you using Notion, Obsidian, or some mind-mapping software?&rdquo;</em></p>
<p>I tried. I really did. I tested every digital tool that promised to boost creativity, enhance focus, or revolutionize note-taking.</p>
<p>But every time I brainstormed digitally, my brain didn’t work the same way.</p>
<p>With paper, I can:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Think freely</strong> without clicking, scrolling, or being distracted by notifications.</li>
<li><strong>Draw connections</strong> with arrows, circles, and messy scribbles that no app can replicate.</li>
<li><strong>Physically slow down</strong>, which somehow speeds up my problem-solving.</li>
</ul>
<p>I don’t use paper because I’m nostalgic. I use it because <strong>it works.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-problem-with-digital-thinking"><strong>The Problem with Digital Thinking</strong></h2>
<p>I love automation. I love shortcuts. I love anything that makes life easier. But when it comes to deep thinking, digital tools have a fatal flaw:</p>
<p>They make <strong>everything too neat.</strong></p>
<p>Typing forces you into a <strong>linear thought process</strong>. You write in straight lines, format as you go, and delete mistakes like they never happened.</p>
<p>But real problem-solving? <strong>It’s messy.</strong></p>
<p>It’s half-written thoughts, sketches, crossed-out ideas, and a page that looks like a conspiracy board before you finally crack the solution.</p>
<p>Digital tools force me into boxes—literally and figuratively. I can’t draw wild arrows connecting random ideas. I can’t scribble thoughts in the margin and come back to them later.</p>
<p>When I write on paper, I’m <strong>not editing as I think.</strong> I’m letting ideas <strong>collide</strong>, not organizing them prematurely. And that’s exactly what I need to get to the right answer.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="paper-is-my-debugging-tool"><strong>Paper is My Debugging Tool</strong></h2>
<p>For some people, thinking happens <strong>on the keyboard</strong>.</p>
<p>For me, thinking happens <strong>with a pen.</strong></p>
<p>It’s not just about notes—it’s about <strong>clarity</strong>. It’s about <strong>processing</strong>. It’s about slowing down just enough to let my brain catch up.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Before I write code, I write on paper.</strong> I map out the logic, draw flowcharts, and outline the structure. By the time I open my editor, I already know the architecture.</li>
<li><strong>Before I solve a bug, I sketch it out.</strong> I diagram the data flow, mark potential breakpoints, and circle points of failure. Seeing it visually helps me understand it faster.</li>
<li><strong>Before I commit to an approach, I let my brain wander on an actual page.</strong> I list pros and cons, explore alternative solutions, and play out scenarios.</li>
</ul>
<p>By the time I finally touch the keyboard, <strong>I already know what I’m doing.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-takeaway"><strong>The Takeaway</strong></h2>
<p>People assume that because we work in tech, we should do everything with tech. But sometimes, the best tool for the job <strong>isn’t the newest or the most advanced</strong>—it’s just the one that works.</p>
<p>No productivity hack replaces <strong>thinking</strong>.<br>
No app mimics <strong>messy creativity</strong>.<br>
No digital shortcut matches the simplicity of pen and paper.</p>
<p>So yeah, I’ll keep using paper. Call me old-school. Call me weird.</p>
<p>But also? <strong>Watch me solve problems faster than you.</strong></p>
<p>Because in a world obsessed with digital productivity, sometimes the real secret weapon is the analog one.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
