<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Reflection on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/reflection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reflection on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.144.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thank You, Little Car: Lessons from the Roads That Raised Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/thank-you-little-car-lessons-roads-that-raised-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/thank-you-little-car-lessons-roads-that-raised-me/</guid>
      <description>A heartfelt reflection on how everyday drives during college shaped a life of gratitude, curiosity, and personal growth.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There was a time in life when <strong>possibility felt limitless</strong> — when each day offered a chance to learn something new, and every small adventure carried meaning. I look back on that chapter with <em>deep appreciation</em>. With a little car and a big sense of curiosity, I explored not just classrooms but entire neighborhoods, local parks, buzzing malls, and quiet stretches of beach.</p>
<p>What stands out now isn’t just <em>where</em> I went, but <em>what</em> those moments taught me. A spontaneous drive could turn into a conversation that shifted my perspective. A walk in the park could spark an idea or a feeling I hadn’t noticed before. Every experience — big or small — helped me grow.</p>
<p>Many of these moments happened during college, but their impact reaches far beyond those years. They taught me to <strong>be open to the unexpected</strong>, to <strong>find value in detours</strong>, and to <strong>appreciate both stillness and movement</strong>.</p>
<p>Today, I carry that energy forward — <em>not as a longing for what was</em>, but as <strong>gratitude</strong> for what those times gave me. They helped shape a version of myself I’m proud of: someone steady, thoughtful, and still curious. The lessons of those early adventures remain part of my everyday life.</p>
<p>Every road taken — planned or spontaneous — added something meaningful to who I am.</p>
<p>And for that, <strong>I’m thankful</strong>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quiet Room</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-quiet-room-life-after-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-quiet-room-life-after-social-media/</guid>
      <description>What I found after closing the door on social media: quiet, moka, and everything just as it was.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After I closed the door on social media, I found myself in a <strong>quiet room</strong>.</p>
<p>No scroll, no buzz, no filters. Just <em>stillness</em>.</p>
<p>And you know what? I didn’t miss it. Not even a little.</p>
<p>Life didn’t change. A couple of friends reached out privately, and it was fun—like running into someone at the market and chatting spontaneously. Maybe others will follow, maybe not. It’s fine. My days are still what they’ve always been: a little chaotic, often beautiful, and somehow always too short.</p>
<p>In this quiet room, I didn’t discover enlightenment or productivity hacks. I didn’t become a new person. I just realized I still like being me—<strong>offline too</strong>.</p>
<p>This blog isn’t a megaphone. It’s a <strong>lamp in a quiet room</strong>. A place to sit down, take off the performance, and speak plainly. If you’ve found your way here, welcome. I’m glad you did.</p>
<p>There’s a <strong>moka on the stove</strong>, quietly bubbling. The chair is yours if you want it.</p>
<p>I don’t know how often I’ll write. I just know that when I do, it will be <em>real</em>. No hashtags. No metrics. Just this.</p>
<p>Thanks for stepping inside.<br>
- D.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
