<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Gratitude on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/gratitude/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gratitude on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.144.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/gratitude/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thank You, Little Car: Lessons from the Roads That Raised Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/thank-you-little-car-lessons-roads-that-raised-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/thank-you-little-car-lessons-roads-that-raised-me/</guid>
      <description>A heartfelt reflection on how everyday drives during college shaped a life of gratitude, curiosity, and personal growth.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There was a time in life when <strong>possibility felt limitless</strong> — when each day offered a chance to learn something new, and every small adventure carried meaning. I look back on that chapter with <em>deep appreciation</em>. With a little car and a big sense of curiosity, I explored not just classrooms but entire neighborhoods, local parks, buzzing malls, and quiet stretches of beach.</p>
<p>What stands out now isn’t just <em>where</em> I went, but <em>what</em> those moments taught me. A spontaneous drive could turn into a conversation that shifted my perspective. A walk in the park could spark an idea or a feeling I hadn’t noticed before. Every experience — big or small — helped me grow.</p>
<p>Many of these moments happened during college, but their impact reaches far beyond those years. They taught me to <strong>be open to the unexpected</strong>, to <strong>find value in detours</strong>, and to <strong>appreciate both stillness and movement</strong>.</p>
<p>Today, I carry that energy forward — <em>not as a longing for what was</em>, but as <strong>gratitude</strong> for what those times gave me. They helped shape a version of myself I’m proud of: someone steady, thoughtful, and still curious. The lessons of those early adventures remain part of my everyday life.</p>
<p>Every road taken — planned or spontaneous — added something meaningful to who I am.</p>
<p>And for that, <strong>I’m thankful</strong>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
