<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Love on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/love/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Love on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.144.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/love/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Love Notes (and Bugs) in the Silence of Home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/love-notes-and-bugs-in-the-silence-of-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/love-notes-and-bugs-in-the-silence-of-home/</guid>
      <description>A love story told in the quiet moments of working from home together.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I work from home in an <strong>old Brooklyn apartment</strong> with high ceilings, creaky floors, and a history that whispers through the walls.</p>
<p>Our study is actually our daughter’s bedroom during off-hours, <strong>repurposed as a workspace</strong> where my wife and I sit at separate desks.<br>
Just enough space to pass between us. Close, but not too close—<strong>perfect for love and concentration.</strong></p>
<p>She’s studying to become an <strong>elementary school teacher</strong>, headphones on, eyes locked on her screen, so intensely focused that I’m convinced she could ignore a fire drill.<br>
I’m right beside her, <strong>lost in lines of PHP code</strong>, wrestling with bugs that refuse to die.</p>
<p>We don’t speak while we work. <strong>Not a word.</strong></p>
<p>It’s not that we don’t want to.<br>
It’s that we <strong>can’t afford to.</strong></p>
<p>Because if I say even a simple <em>&ldquo;Hey&rdquo;</em>, <strong>it’s over.</strong></p>
<p>Our daughter would appear out of nowhere, demanding to know why <strong>unicorns are magical</strong> or how <strong>rainbows work.</strong><br>
The baby would start crying, because <strong>chaos loves company.</strong><br>
And just like that, our fragile focus would shatter into a million pieces.</p>
<p>So, instead? <strong>We live in silence.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="secret-messages-without-saying-a-word"><strong>Secret Messages (Without Saying a Word)</strong></h2>
<p>Back when we first met at work, we <strong>flirted from separate desks</strong>, sending each other cheeky messages on the company chat.<br>
We couldn’t talk aloud—professionalism and all—but we found ways to make each other smile.</p>
<p>Not much has changed. <strong>We still send each other secret notes.</strong></p>
<p>Except now, they’re digital.</p>
<p>I’ll text her from two desks away:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>“Did you see the email?”</strong> (<em>Translation: “I miss you.”</em>)</li>
<li><strong>“What’s for lunch?”</strong> (<em>Translation: “You’re beautiful.”</em>)</li>
<li><strong>“This bug is killing me.”</strong> (<em>Translation: “I love you.”</em>)</li>
</ul>
<p>Our messages are <strong>coded love notes</strong>, little signals in the middle of the workday.<br>
They keep us connected, even in silence.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="stolen-glances-and-hidden-smiles"><strong>Stolen Glances and Hidden Smiles</strong></h2>
<p>I steal glances at her when she’s not looking.</p>
<p>Her laptop is open, her notes are neatly organized, and she has that look of <strong>fierce determination</strong> that could move mountains.</p>
<p>She’s beautiful, even when she’s stressed, even when she’s muttering facts under her breath.<br>
I want to tell her. But I don’t.</p>
<p>Because if I break the silence? <strong>The whole system collapses.</strong></p>
<p>We’d lose focus.<br>
Our daughter would rush in with questions.<br>
The baby would follow.<br>
And our carefully structured workday would spiral into <strong>pure chaos.</strong></p>
<p>So, instead, <strong>I stay silent.</strong><br>
And somehow, that silence says everything.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="why-this-silence-is-my-favorite-sound"><strong>Why This Silence is My Favorite Sound</strong></h2>
<p>Sometimes, I hate working from home.<br>
I hate how <strong>work and life blur together</strong>, how emails never stop, how meetings pop up out of nowhere.</p>
<p>But <strong>I love this.</strong></p>
<p>I love this strange, quiet dance we do.<br>
I love the way we communicate without words, how we’re together yet apart.</p>
<p>I love the way she chews on her pen when she’s thinking, the way she sighs when she’s frustrated, the way she whispers to herself while studying.<br>
I love every little thing <strong>she doesn’t realize I notice.</strong></p>
<p>And even though she won’t look up, even though she’s too busy to see me staring—</p>
<p><strong>I smile.</strong></p>
<p>Because she’s mine.<br>
She’s always been mine.<br>
And in this <strong>shared silence, we’re still falling in love.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-invisible-love-story"><strong>The Invisible Love Story</strong></h2>
<p>This is our life.<br>
Our love.<br>
Our silence.</p>
<p>And I wouldn’t trade it for anything.</p>
<p>It’s not always perfect. We fight. We get tired. We get stressed.<br>
But in this space, in this shared silence, <strong>we find each other.</strong></p>
<p>It’s not about grand gestures. It’s not about dramatic declarations.<br>
It’s about <strong>the little things.</strong></p>
<p>It’s the way she hands me my coffee without a word.<br>
It’s the way I fix her chair without her asking.<br>
It’s the way we both know when the other needs a break, even if we don’t say it.</p>
<p>It’s the way <strong>our love speaks in silence.</strong></p>
<p>And even on the hardest days, even when the baby cries, even when the code breaks—</p>
<p>I look at her and I know:</p>
<p><strong>This is exactly where I’m meant to be.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
