<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Self-Discovery on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/self-discovery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Self-Discovery on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.144.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/self-discovery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I Never Thought I’d Grow a Beard (But Here We Are)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-never-thought-id-grow-a-beard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-never-thought-id-grow-a-beard/</guid>
      <description>Growing a beard was never in my plans. But this accidental experiment taught me more about identity than I expected.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve never been a <strong>beard guy.</strong></p>
<p>For most of my life, I thought of facial hair as something that just <strong>happened</strong> to other people—like an automatic feature that unlocked at a certain age. I’d see guys with <strong>thick, full beards</strong> and think, <em>Yeah, that’s just not for me.</em></p>
<p>It wasn’t even a conscious decision. It was more like an unspoken agreement with myself:</p>
<p>✔ <strong>I shave because I always have.</strong><br>
✔ <strong>I’m just not a beard person.</strong></p>
<p>And then, one day&hellip; <strong>I didn’t shave.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-accidental-beard-experiment"><strong>The Accidental Beard Experiment</strong></h2>
<p>I didn’t wake up one morning and decide, <em>I shall grow a beard!</em></p>
<p>It started with a few skipped shaves. Life got busy. I got lazy. And before I knew it, my face had <strong>more stubble than usual.</strong></p>
<p>Normally, this would have <strong>annoyed me.</strong> But this time?</p>
<p>I let it stay.</p>
<p>At first, it felt weird—like my <strong>own face was betraying me.</strong> I&rsquo;d catch glimpses of myself and think, <em>Who is this guy?</em></p>
<p>The <strong>itchy phase</strong> was real.<br>
The <strong>awkward patchy phase</strong> was even more real.</p>
<p>But the strangest part?</p>
<p>I <strong>kind of liked it.</strong></p>
<p>I started noticing little things:</p>
<ul>
<li>It made me <strong>look older</strong> (or maybe just <em>different</em>).</li>
<li>It <strong>changed the shape of my face.</strong></li>
<li>I kept catching myself <strong>stroking my chin like some kind of wise philosopher.</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>And the itch? It wasn’t as bad as I thought. More like a <strong>reminder</strong> that something was changing.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="why-growing-a-beard-felt-so-different"><strong>Why Growing a Beard Felt So… Different</strong></h2>
<p>It’s funny how something as simple as <strong>not shaving</strong> can change the way you see yourself.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>I looked different.</strong> My face had more definition. My jawline felt stronger. It was like a <strong>real-life Instagram filter.</strong></li>
<li><strong>I felt different.</strong> There was something about it—maybe confidence, maybe curiosity—that made me feel more <strong>deliberate.</strong> Like I had <em>made a choice</em>, even if that choice was just to&hellip; not shave.</li>
<li><strong>Other people noticed.</strong>
<ul>
<li><em>&ldquo;Oh, you’re growing it out?&rdquo;</em></li>
<li><em>&ldquo;Hey, that actually suits you.&rdquo;</em></li>
<li><em>&ldquo;You look… more Italian now.&rdquo;</em> (<em>That one made me laugh.</em>)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I wasn’t prepared for how much <strong>other people</strong> would comment on it. It was like I had <strong>changed something huge</strong>, when all I did was&hellip; <em>nothing.</em></p>
<p>And every time someone mentioned it, I felt this weird mix of <strong>pride and discomfort.</strong> Like I was being <strong>seen in a new way</strong>—and I wasn’t sure how I felt about that.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="what-i-learned-from-letting-my-face-do-its-thing"><strong>What I Learned From Letting My Face Do Its Thing</strong></h2>
<p>Growing a beard <strong>didn’t change my life.</strong></p>
<p>But it did make me <strong>realize something important.</strong></p>
<p>So many of the things we believe about ourselves—our <strong>“defaults”</strong>—aren’t actually rules. They’re just <strong>habits.</strong></p>
<p>For years, I thought:<br>
✔ <em>I’m a clean-shaven guy.</em><br>
✔ <em>Beards don’t suit me.</em><br>
✔ <em>This is just how I look.</em></p>
<p>And then, in a matter of weeks, those “truths” <strong>disappeared.</strong></p>
<p>It made me wonder:<br>
<em>How many other things do I believe about myself just because they’ve always been that way?</em></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>I’m not a morning person.</strong> (<em>Or am I just used to staying up late?</em>)</li>
<li><strong>I don’t like public speaking.</strong> (<em>Or have I just never given it a real chance?</em>)</li>
<li><strong>I’m not a beard guy.</strong> (<em>Or did I just never let it grow long enough to find out?</em>)</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s strange how something as simple as <strong>not shaving</strong> can make you question so much more.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="will-i-keep-it"><strong>Will I Keep It?</strong></h2>
<p>I don’t know yet. Maybe I’ll <strong>shave it off next week.</strong><br>
Maybe I’ll <strong>keep it longer.</strong></p>
<p>Right now, I’m just <strong>letting it be.</strong></p>
<p>No expectations. No rules. Just <strong>curiosity.</strong></p>
<p>But either way, this isn’t really about the beard.</p>
<p>It’s about realizing that sometimes, <strong>the smallest change can make you see yourself in a whole new way.</strong></p>
<p>And honestly? <strong>That’s worth exploring.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
