<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Cognition on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/cognition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cognition on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.144.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/cognition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Son Is Smarter Than ChatGPT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-son-is-smarter-than-chatgpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-son-is-smarter-than-chatgpt/</guid>
      <description>A humorous but scientific deep dive into the insane things my baby son is already doing — from moral judgments to number sense, multilingual mastery, and real-time neural DevOps.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="my-son-is-smarter-than-chatgpt">My Son Is Smarter Than ChatGPT</h2>
<p>I thought I was smart. I work in tech. I troubleshoot complex systems. I optimize databases. I write code that doesn’t crash on Fridays. But then I had a son.</p>
<p>And slowly, I began to realize something deeply humbling:<br>
This tiny human — who still occasionally tries to eat my slipper — is doing things that would blow the minds of most adults I know. Including, at times, myself.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="he-tasted-the-world--literally">He Tasted the World — Literally</h3>
<p>Babies have <strong>30,000 taste buds</strong>. Not just on the tongue — all over the mouth. That’s <strong>three times</strong> more than adults.</p>
<p>When my son eats mashed banana, it’s not just a snack. It’s a multi-sensory fireworks display. Imagine if <em>you</em> could taste shapes, or feel sounds.</p>
<p>Some researchers believe that babies might experience <strong>synesthesia</strong> early on — a cross-wiring of the senses. That means he may literally <strong>taste textures</strong> or <strong>feel sounds</strong> before those brain connections settle down.</p>
<p>Honestly, it explains a lot. Including the deep betrayal he expressed after tasting broccoli.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="he-saw-things-ill-never-see-again">He Saw Things I’ll Never See Again</h3>
<p>At one point, my son could recognize <strong>every human face</strong> — no matter the ethnicity. Even <em>monkeys</em>. Yes, monkeys.</p>
<p>But then came <strong>perceptual narrowing</strong>: the brain’s way of optimizing for the environment. Like a smart algorithm that prunes unused inputs, his brain decided, <em>“We’re not seeing a lot of lemurs around here. Let’s drop that subroutine.”</em></p>
<p>Now he’s laser-focused on familiar faces and sounds — namely, the ones he sees and hears at home in Italian and English.</p>
<p>For a brief time, though, he had global facial and phonetic superpowers.</p>
<p>And we call adults smart?</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="he-predicted-physics-before-sitting-up">He Predicted Physics Before Sitting Up</h3>
<p>At just four months, he understood something was about to touch him before it did. His brain linked <strong>vision and touch</strong>.</p>
<p>This is called <strong>peripersonal space awareness</strong>, and it means he’s already tracking where his body ends and the world begins. Not bad for someone who still poops in Morse code.</p>
<p>By eight months, babies <strong>expect sensory outcomes</strong> — and are <em>surprised</em> when they don’t happen. That’s physics prediction.<br>
That’s <strong>if-then logic</strong>, built in.</p>
<p>And unlike ChatGPT, he didn’t need a neural net refresh to understand object permanence.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="he-could-hear-every-language-on-earth">He Could Hear Every Language on Earth</h3>
<p>Until recently, my son could distinguish all the speech sounds in every known language — including ones <em>we don’t even speak</em>.</p>
<p>Hindi? Yup. Zulu clicks? Definitely.</p>
<p>But as he tuned into our two native languages — Italian and English — he lost the ability to hear contrasts he no longer needed.</p>
<p>This is called <strong>phonetic narrowing</strong>. It’s like a language engine optimizing for local data.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, he now says “banana” like it’s a mission-critical API call. Repeated hourly.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="his-legs-had-the-code-his-muscles-didnt">His Legs Had the Code. His Muscles Didn’t.</h3>
<p>There’s this old myth that babies lose the <strong>stepping reflex</strong> by 2 months. Not true.</p>
<p>What actually happens? Their legs get heavier with adorable fat, and the muscles can’t lift them anymore. The code is still running — the hardware just chokes.</p>
<p>In fact, one study showed that babies who &ldquo;lost&rdquo; the stepping reflex started doing it again… <em>in water</em>, where their legs were lighter.</p>
<p>So yes — my son had the <strong>walking software pre-installed</strong>, he was just waiting for the <strong>driver update</strong>.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="he-knows-if-youre-a-good-person">He Knows If You&rsquo;re a Good Person</h3>
<p>Science shows that babies — around a year old — can distinguish between “helpful” and “mean” behavior.</p>
<p>They even <strong>prefer nice puppets</strong> over mean ones. Without being told.</p>
<p>That’s <strong>proto-moral reasoning</strong>. Meanwhile, I still second-guess whether I was rude in that Slack message 6 hours ago.</p>
<p>If my son throws a puff snack at you, just know: it’s not random. It’s social feedback.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="he-does-math-the-impossible-kind">He Does Math. The Impossible Kind.</h3>
<p>If you show a baby a simple math &ldquo;trick&rdquo; — like 1 toy going behind a screen, then another, and when the screen lifts there’s still only 1 toy — they stare longer.</p>
<p>That’s because they know something’s off.<br>
It’s called <strong>number sense</strong>.</p>
<p>No formulas, no calculator. Just raw violation detection.<br>
It’s basically <strong>unit testing for logic</strong> — except done silently, with judgmental eye contact.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="babbling--precompiled-language">Babbling = Precompiled Language</h3>
<p>When he babbles “ba ba ba,” he’s not just making noise.</p>
<p>He’s compiling syntax.</p>
<p>Studies show that even deaf babies exposed to sign language will <strong>babble with their hands</strong>. Repetitive, rhythmic gestures that look just like spoken babbling.</p>
<p>So language prep isn’t about mouths — it’s about <strong>brains</strong>. And the brain doesn’t care whether you speak with your tongue or your fingers.</p>
<p>He’s not learning language. He’s already running the <strong>beta release</strong>.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="his-brain-is-basically-devops-on-steroids">His Brain Is Basically DevOps on Steroids</h3>
<p>Here’s what’s running during nap time:</p>
<ul>
<li>Neural pruning</li>
<li>REM-driven memory consolidation</li>
<li>Cortisol modulation</li>
<li>Synaptic reorganization</li>
<li>Night mode updates</li>
</ul>
<p>Sleep isn’t passive — it’s maintenance.<br>
It’s <strong>unsupervised machine learning</strong>, every night.</p>
<p>Which is why I guard nap time like a sysadmin guards uptime.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="final-thoughts">Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>Every day, I write code. I optimize systems. I fix bugs.</p>
<p>But none of it — <strong>none of it</strong> — compares to what I see unfolding in this curious, gurgling, banana-obsessed small human.</p>
<p>He’s learning language with no tutorials. Predicting physics with no math. Judging your character before you say a word.</p>
<p>He’s not just smart.</p>
<p>He’s <strong>smarter than ChatGPT</strong>.</p>
<p>And when I ask him something…<br>
He looks me in the eye…</p>
<p>…and says: <em>&ldquo;Banana.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p>Which, honestly, is probably all the wisdom I need.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
