<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>File Formats on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/file-formats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in File Formats on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.144.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/file-formats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why You Should Save Images as PNG Instead of JPG (Most of the Time!)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-save-images-as-png-instead-of-jpg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-save-images-as-png-instead-of-jpg/</guid>
      <description>A breakdown of why PNG is often the better choice over JPG—because nobody wants their images looking like they were printed on a potato.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So, you’re about to save an image, and that little dropdown asks: <strong>PNG or JPG?</strong> And suddenly, you pause. You squint at the screen, question all your life choices, and wonder why this is even a decision you have to make.</p>
<p>Well, let me tell you—<strong>it is</strong>. Because choosing the wrong format can absolutely ruin your image. And you won’t even realize it until it’s too late, like when you zoom in and see that your once-crisp design now looks like it was printed on a cereal box from the ‘90s.</p>
<p>Let’s get into it.</p>
<h2 id="1-png-keeps-your-image-sharpjpg-smudges-it-like-a-greasy-fingerprint"><strong>1. PNG Keeps Your Image Sharp—JPG Smudges It Like a Greasy Fingerprint</strong></h2>
<p>You ever seen a JPG up close? It’s not pretty.</p>
<p>JPG <strong>compresses</strong> images by basically throwing away data, which means the more you save, the more quality you lose. It’s like making a photocopy of a photocopy—after a while, everything looks a little&hellip; <em>off</em>.</p>
<p>PNG, on the other hand, keeps <strong>everything</strong>. Every pixel, every little detail. If you’ve ever saved a screenshot of text as a JPG and then wondered why it suddenly looks like it was written in crayon, you already know the struggle.</p>
<p>So, if you care about <strong>keeping things crisp</strong>, <strong>PNG is your best friend</strong>.</p>
<h2 id="2-transparency-because-not-everything-needs-a-white-box-around-it"><strong>2. Transparency. Because Not Everything Needs a White Box Around It.</strong></h2>
<p>Ever tried saving a logo as a JPG and ended up with an ugly white background? Yeah. That’s because JPG doesn’t do <strong>transparency</strong>.</p>
<p>PNG? <strong>Perfectly clean, invisible backgrounds.</strong></p>
<p>This is huge if you’re working with <strong>logos, icons, or anything you need to layer over other images</strong>. If you’re making graphics and saving them as JPGs, you’re basically giving yourself extra work because now you have to go back and remove that stupid white box.</p>
<p>Or, you know, just <strong>use PNG from the start and save yourself the headache</strong>.</p>
<h2 id="3-png-keeps-text-and-sharp-lines-looking-sharpjpg-butchers-them"><strong>3. PNG Keeps Text and Sharp Lines Looking Sharp—JPG Butchers Them</strong></h2>
<p>JPG has a bad habit of turning sharp edges into <strong>blurry, blocky nonsense</strong>. Letters, graphs, clean vector lines—it all gets smudged like someone took their thumb and rubbed it across the screen.</p>
<p>If you’re making infographics, charts, UI elements, or anything with text, <strong>stick with PNG</strong>. Otherwise, you’ll zoom in and wonder why your carefully designed text now looks like it was pulled from an old fax machine.</p>
<p>And no, increasing the JPG quality to 100% won’t <em>completely</em> fix it. That’s like putting a band-aid on a broken bone.</p>
<h2 id="4-color-gradients-stay-smooth-in-pngjpg-turns-them-into-a-stripey-mess"><strong>4. Color Gradients Stay Smooth in PNG—JPG Turns Them Into a Stripey Mess</strong></h2>
<p>You ever seen an image where a soft color gradient turns into a series of ugly bands instead of a smooth transition? That’s JPG compression <strong>at work</strong>.</p>
<p>PNG keeps <strong>all</strong> the subtle color details, while JPG tries to “simplify” them, which is just a fancy way of saying “ruins them.”</p>
<p>If you’re working on <strong>art, backgrounds, or anything with a soft color fade</strong>, don’t even think about saving as JPG. Unless you <em>like</em> your images looking like they came from an early 2000s PowerPoint slide.</p>
<h2 id="5-you-can-save-png-over-and-over-without-losing-qualityjpg-degrades-every-time"><strong>5. You Can Save PNG Over and Over Without Losing Quality—JPG Degrades Every Time</strong></h2>
<p>JPG is like a VHS tape. Every time you copy, edit, and save it, the quality <strong>gets worse</strong>.</p>
<p>PNG? <strong>Doesn’t budge.</strong></p>
<p>This is <strong>huge</strong> if you’re working on something that requires multiple edits. Save as PNG, and you’ll always have a clean, perfect file. Save as JPG, and after a few rounds, you’ll be looking at something that resembles abstract art—but not in a good way.</p>
<p>Also, if you’re archiving old photos, <strong>PNG is the way to go</strong>. Because one day, Future You is gonna open that JPG and ask, <em>“Why does this look like a pixelated disaster?”</em></p>
<h2 id="but-waitwhen-is-jpg-actually-better"><strong>But Wait—When Is JPG Actually Better?</strong></h2>
<p>Look, JPG <strong>isn’t evil</strong>. It’s just… situational.</p>
<p>If you’re dealing with <strong>big photos and need to save space</strong>, JPG is fine. It’s great for sharing images on the web, sending memes, or saving a bunch of random pictures that <strong>don’t need to be perfect</strong>.</p>
<p>But if you’re working with <strong>logos, text, sharp details, or anything you want to keep pristine</strong>, <strong>PNG is the move</strong>.</p>
<h2 id="final-thoughts"><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></h2>
<p>So next time you’re about to hit &ldquo;Save As,&rdquo; ask yourself: <strong>Do I care about transparency? Do I need sharp edges? Will I be editing this later?</strong> If the answer to any of those is yes, <strong>PNG all the way</strong>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
