<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal Experience on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/personal-experience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal Experience on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.144.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/personal-experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notion: The External Brain That Finally Works for Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/notion-external-brain-that-works-for-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/notion-external-brain-that-works-for-me/</guid>
      <description>Struggling to keep track of your ideas and tasks? Discover why Notion is the external brain I never knew I needed.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For most of my life, I’ve been at war with <strong>my own memory</strong>.</p>
<p>I’m great at solving problems, debugging complex code, and figuring out tricky logic flows. But ask me where I saved that important note from last week? <strong>Gone.</strong> Ask me what I was about to do five seconds ago? <strong>No idea.</strong></p>
<p>My brain has this incredible ability to cling to <strong>completely useless information</strong> while ruthlessly discarding the things I actually need.</p>
<p>I’ve spent <strong>years</strong> searching for a way to keep my thoughts, projects, and tasks organized. I tried:</p>
<p>✔ <strong>Sticky notes</strong> (<em>good luck finding them when I actually need them&hellip; they vanish into another dimension</em>).<br>
✔ <strong>To-do list apps</strong> (<em>too rigid, too limited, abandoned after a week</em>).<br>
✔ <strong>Google Docs</strong> (<em>a black hole where ideas go to die</em>).<br>
✔ <strong>My own memory</strong> (<em>don’t even ask</em>).</p>
<p>Nothing worked.</p>
<p>Then I stumbled upon <strong>Notion</strong>, and suddenly, <strong>my brain had a backup system.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="why-notion-works-for-me-when-everything-else-failed"><strong>Why Notion Works for Me (When Everything Else Failed)</strong></h2>
<p>I’ve always been skeptical of <strong>“all-in-one” productivity tools</strong>.</p>
<p>Every app promises to be <strong>the last one you’ll ever need</strong>—and every single time, I end up uninstalling it because it’s either <strong>too simple, too complicated, or just doesn’t fit how I think</strong>.</p>
<p>Notion is the first one that actually <strong>adapts to me</strong>.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>It’s a notes app, task manager, and database—all at once.</strong> But only if I want it to be. I can keep it simple or build a full-blown project tracker. It’s a <strong>blank canvas</strong>, and I decide the rules.</li>
<li><strong>The free version is actually good.</strong> Unlike Obsidian, I don’t have to pay just to sync across devices. Unlike Evernote, I don’t feel like I’m using <strong>a relic from 2010</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>I can publish and share pages instantly.</strong> No fighting with exporting or formatting—one click, and it’s a webpage. Done.</li>
<li><strong>I can dump everything into it, and nothing gets lost.</strong> Ideas, tasks, half-baked thoughts—<strong>they all have a home now.</strong> And somehow, I can actually <strong>find them when I need them</strong>.</li>
</ul>
<p>Before Notion, my workflow was <strong>a mess</strong>.</p>
<ul>
<li>Notes buried in <strong>random text files</strong>.</li>
<li>Ideas scattered in <strong>Google Keep</strong>, which I’d forget existed.</li>
<li>Tasks floating in my head, <strong>patiently waiting to be forgotten</strong>.</li>
</ul>
<p>Now? <strong>Everything is in one place.</strong> Exactly where I expect it to be.</p>
<p>It’s like having my own <strong>personal knowledge base</strong>, and for the first time, I actually <strong>trust my system</strong>.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="what-about-the-offline-mode"><strong>What About the Offline Mode?</strong></h2>
<p>Yeah, I know—<strong>Notion doesn’t work offline.</strong></p>
<p>For most people, that’s a deal-breaker. But for me? <strong>It doesn’t matter.</strong></p>
<p>I work <strong>online all the time</strong>. My job as a developer is remote. My files live in the cloud. My meetings are on video calls.</p>
<p>The only time I’d need offline notes is if I were <strong>stuck in a cabin with no internet</strong>—and at that point, I have <strong>bigger problems than note-taking.</strong></p>
<p>Like figuring out <strong>how to survive without Stack Overflow.</strong></p>
<p>For my actual, <strong>daily reality</strong>, Notion’s <strong>always-online</strong> approach isn’t a limitation.<br>
<strong>It’s just how I already work.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-takeaway"><strong>The Takeaway</strong></h2>
<p>I didn’t think I needed Notion.</p>
<p>I thought I just needed to <strong>be more disciplined</strong> or find the “right” system to organize my thoughts. I assumed <strong>I was just bad at remembering things</strong>, and that was that.</p>
<p>But now? <strong>I can’t imagine functioning without it.</strong></p>
<p>If you’ve ever felt like your thoughts are <strong>scattered across a dozen places</strong>, if you struggle to <strong>remember things you actually need</strong>, if you’ve tried <strong>every productivity tool and nothing stuck</strong>—</p>
<p><strong>Notion might be exactly what your brain has been waiting for.</strong></p>
<p>And unlike my real brain, <strong>it actually remembers things.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Every Developer Writes Code (Whether They Admit It or Not)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-every-developer-writes-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-every-developer-writes-code/</guid>
      <description>Coding isn’t as glamorous as it seems. Discover the hilariously relatable stages every developer goes through while writing code.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>People think developers write code in a smooth, structured way—like some kind of <strong>elegant digital architect</strong>.</p>
<p>They imagine us sitting in front of a screen, effortlessly typing out <strong>clean, efficient, well-documented functions</strong>, sipping coffee, and feeling <strong>in complete control</strong>.</p>
<p>Yeah. <strong>No.</strong></p>
<p>Here’s what <strong>actually</strong> happens.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="step-1-the-grand-vision-"><strong>Step 1: The Grand Vision</strong> (<em>&ldquo;I know exactly how to do this.&rdquo;</em>)</h2>
<p>You get the ticket. You think, <em>Oh, this is simple.</em></p>
<p>You crack your knuckles. Open your editor. Start typing with confidence.</p>
<p>You’re in the <strong>zone</strong>. The code is flowing. You are an unstoppable force. A <strong>coding genius.</strong> You should write a book about this.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="step-2-the-first-run-"><strong>Step 2: The First Run</strong> (<em>&ldquo;Why is it broken?&rdquo;</em>)</h2>
<p>You confidently hit run.</p>
<p><strong>Immediate error.</strong></p>
<p>Okay, no problem. A minor fix. You run it again.</p>
<p><strong>Different error.</strong></p>
<p>You frown. Maybe you mistyped something? You check the function names. Everything <strong>looks</strong> correct.</p>
<p>Run it again.</p>
<p>Now it’s <strong>really</strong> broken.</p>
<p>This is the moment you realize: <em>You have no idea what you’re doing.</em></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="step-3-the-google-phase-"><strong>Step 3: The Google Phase</strong> (<em>&ldquo;Surely someone has solved this before.&rdquo;</em>)</h2>
<p>You open Google. You type something completely ridiculous, like:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>&ldquo;PHP array error help please what is happening&rdquo;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>You find a <strong>Stack Overflow thread from 2012.</strong> Someone had a similar problem. The top answer is:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>&ldquo;Have you tried restarting your computer?&rdquo;</em></p></blockquote>
<p>You scroll down. Another answer <strong>looks promising.</strong> You copy and paste the code <strong>without reading it.</strong></p>
<p>It <strong>doesn&rsquo;t work.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="step-4-the-deep-spiral-"><strong>Step 4: The Deep Spiral</strong> (<em>&ldquo;I have made a terrible mistake.&rdquo;</em>)</h2>
<p>You start adding <strong>random print statements.</strong></p>
<p>You go <strong>deeper</strong> into Stack Overflow. You start reading answers from <strong>people who sound like they barely know what they’re doing</strong>—but at this point, you’re desperate.</p>
<p>You begin <strong>questioning your life choices.</strong></p>
<p><em>Maybe I should’ve been a chef? People always need food. Nobody ever asks a steak why it’s not iterating through an array properly.</em></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="step-5-the-accidental-fix-"><strong>Step 5: The Accidental Fix</strong> (<em>&ldquo;Wait&hellip; what?&rdquo;)</em></h2>
<p>You change <strong>one tiny thing</strong>—maybe a missing semicolon, maybe a different variable name—and suddenly…</p>
<p><strong>It works.</strong></p>
<p>You <strong>don’t know why.</strong> You <strong>don’t care.</strong></p>
<p>You immediately push the fix <strong>before it breaks again.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="step-6-the--"><strong>Step 6: The &ldquo;Good Enough&rdquo; Phase</strong> (<em>&ldquo;I’ll refactor this later.&rdquo;</em>)</h2>
<p>You know the code is <strong>messy.</strong> You <strong>know</strong> future-you will hate this.</p>
<p>But you tell yourself:</p>
<p><em>&ldquo;I’ll clean it up later.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p><strong>You never do.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="step-7-the-code-review-horror-"><strong>Step 7: The Code Review Horror</strong> (<em>&ldquo;What was I thinking?&rdquo;</em>)</h2>
<p>Two weeks later, someone <strong>reviews your code.</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>&ldquo;Hey, why is there a <code>console.log('WHY IS THIS BROKEN')</code> in here?&rdquo;</strong></p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>&ldquo;Is this function name supposed to be <code>fixThisPleaseFinal_v3()</code>?&rdquo;</strong></p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>&ldquo;Did you… copy this from Stack Overflow?&rdquo;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>You <strong>avoid eye contact.</strong> You <strong>pretend you didn’t see the comments.</strong></p>
<p>You <strong>consider changing your name and moving to another country.</strong></p>
<p>But eventually, you fix it. You push the final version. The PR gets approved.</p>
<p>And then…</p>
<p>A new ticket comes in.</p>
<p>And the <strong>cycle begins again.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I, a Programmer, Still Use Paper Like It’s 1999</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-i-a-programmer-still-use-paper-like-its-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-i-a-programmer-still-use-paper-like-its-1999/</guid>
      <description>Digital tools are powerful, but when it comes to problem-solving, nothing beats paper. Here’s why I, a programmer, still use analog methods.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="why-i-a-programmer-still-use-paper-like-its-1999"><strong>Why I, a Programmer, Still Use Paper Like It’s 1999</strong></h1>
<p>I spend my entire day in front of a screen—writing code, debugging, fixing issues. Everything I do is digital.</p>
<p>And yet, whenever I need to <strong>truly think</strong>, whenever I need to <strong>solve a problem</strong>, I reach for something ancient.</p>
<p><strong>Paper.</strong></p>
<p>Yes, real, dead-tree, old-school <strong>paper</strong>. With an <strong>actual pen.</strong> No stylus, no tablet. Just ink and a blank page.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="why-do-i-do-this"><strong>Why Do I Do This?</strong></h2>
<p>People at my last job called me old-school. Some thought I was joking.</p>
<p><em>&ldquo;You’re a programmer, why aren’t you using Notion, Obsidian, or some mind-mapping software?&rdquo;</em></p>
<p>I tried. I really did. I tested every digital tool that promised to boost creativity, enhance focus, or revolutionize note-taking.</p>
<p>But every time I brainstormed digitally, my brain didn’t work the same way.</p>
<p>With paper, I can:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Think freely</strong> without clicking, scrolling, or being distracted by notifications.</li>
<li><strong>Draw connections</strong> with arrows, circles, and messy scribbles that no app can replicate.</li>
<li><strong>Physically slow down</strong>, which somehow speeds up my problem-solving.</li>
</ul>
<p>I don’t use paper because I’m nostalgic. I use it because <strong>it works.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-problem-with-digital-thinking"><strong>The Problem with Digital Thinking</strong></h2>
<p>I love automation. I love shortcuts. I love anything that makes life easier. But when it comes to deep thinking, digital tools have a fatal flaw:</p>
<p>They make <strong>everything too neat.</strong></p>
<p>Typing forces you into a <strong>linear thought process</strong>. You write in straight lines, format as you go, and delete mistakes like they never happened.</p>
<p>But real problem-solving? <strong>It’s messy.</strong></p>
<p>It’s half-written thoughts, sketches, crossed-out ideas, and a page that looks like a conspiracy board before you finally crack the solution.</p>
<p>Digital tools force me into boxes—literally and figuratively. I can’t draw wild arrows connecting random ideas. I can’t scribble thoughts in the margin and come back to them later.</p>
<p>When I write on paper, I’m <strong>not editing as I think.</strong> I’m letting ideas <strong>collide</strong>, not organizing them prematurely. And that’s exactly what I need to get to the right answer.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="paper-is-my-debugging-tool"><strong>Paper is My Debugging Tool</strong></h2>
<p>For some people, thinking happens <strong>on the keyboard</strong>.</p>
<p>For me, thinking happens <strong>with a pen.</strong></p>
<p>It’s not just about notes—it’s about <strong>clarity</strong>. It’s about <strong>processing</strong>. It’s about slowing down just enough to let my brain catch up.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Before I write code, I write on paper.</strong> I map out the logic, draw flowcharts, and outline the structure. By the time I open my editor, I already know the architecture.</li>
<li><strong>Before I solve a bug, I sketch it out.</strong> I diagram the data flow, mark potential breakpoints, and circle points of failure. Seeing it visually helps me understand it faster.</li>
<li><strong>Before I commit to an approach, I let my brain wander on an actual page.</strong> I list pros and cons, explore alternative solutions, and play out scenarios.</li>
</ul>
<p>By the time I finally touch the keyboard, <strong>I already know what I’m doing.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-takeaway"><strong>The Takeaway</strong></h2>
<p>People assume that because we work in tech, we should do everything with tech. But sometimes, the best tool for the job <strong>isn’t the newest or the most advanced</strong>—it’s just the one that works.</p>
<p>No productivity hack replaces <strong>thinking</strong>.<br>
No app mimics <strong>messy creativity</strong>.<br>
No digital shortcut matches the simplicity of pen and paper.</p>
<p>So yeah, I’ll keep using paper. Call me old-school. Call me weird.</p>
<p>But also? <strong>Watch me solve problems faster than you.</strong></p>
<p>Because in a world obsessed with digital productivity, sometimes the real secret weapon is the analog one.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Never-Ending Search for the Perfect App: Why I Can’t Stop Downloading</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/never-ending-search-for-the-perfect-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/never-ending-search-for-the-perfect-app/</guid>
      <description>Obsessed with finding the perfect app? You’re not alone. Join me on my endless quest for the ultimate productivity tools.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some people spend their free time <strong>watching movies, playing games, or reading books</strong>.<br>
I spend mine on an endless, slightly obsessive search for <strong>the perfect app.</strong></p>
<p>It doesn’t matter what it is—<strong>file manager, calendar, task manager, note-taking app</strong>—if I use it daily, I want it to be <em>just right</em>.</p>
<p>But here’s the problem: <strong>it never is.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-app-store-illusion"><strong>The App Store Illusion</strong></h2>
<p>It always starts the same way.</p>
<p>I convince myself that somewhere, hidden among a sea of <strong>mediocre software</strong>, <strong>the perfect app exists</strong>.</p>
<p>So I start searching.<br>
Reading reviews.<br>
Watching <strong>YouTube comparisons at 2x speed</strong>.<br>
Checking <strong>Reddit threads full of people just like me</strong>—people who have fallen down the same rabbit hole.</p>
<p>I get lost in endless lists like:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>“Top 10 Productivity Apps You Need.”</em></li>
<li><em>“Best File Managers for Windows and iPhone.”</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Eventually, I find something <strong>promising</strong>.</p>
<p>I download it, open it, start setting it up… and then the realization hits:</p>
<p><strong>Something is off.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The interface is <em>almost</em> perfect, but there’s <strong>one weird design choice</strong> that drives me insane.</li>
<li>The features are great, but <strong>why is there a subscription for this?</strong></li>
<li>It’s perfect on <strong>iPhone</strong>, but the <strong>Windows version looks like it was built in 2009</strong> and abandoned.</li>
<li>It’s perfect on <strong>Windows</strong>, but the <strong>iPhone version syncs once every full moon</strong>.</li>
</ul>
<p>And just like that, <strong>the cycle continues</strong>.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="why-do-i-do-this-to-myself"><strong>Why Do I Do This to Myself?</strong></h2>
<p>I know what you’re thinking:</p>
<p><em>&ldquo;Why not just pick one and move on?&rdquo;</em></p>
<p>Because that’s what <strong>normal people</strong> do. But my brain <strong>doesn’t work that way</strong>.</p>
<p>I need <strong>flow</strong> in my tools. If I open an app and something feels <strong>even slightly frustrating</strong>, it’s like an <strong>itch I can’t scratch</strong>.<br>
I’ll notice it <strong>every time</strong> I use it. And once I notice it? I <strong>can’t un-notice it</strong>.</p>
<p>I have a <strong>zero-tolerance policy</strong> for inefficiency:</p>
<p>✔ <strong>If an app takes more than two clicks</strong> to do something that should take one, it’s dead to me.<br>
✔ <strong>If it’s ugly</strong> or the design is inconsistent, I won’t use it, <strong>no matter how powerful it is</strong>.<br>
✔ <strong>If it’s perfect but has a monthly subscription,</strong> I will uninstall it <strong>on principle</strong>.</p>
<p>I want my apps to feel <strong>invisible</strong>, like they don’t exist. They should <strong>just work</strong> without reminding me they’re there.</p>
<p>The worst part?</p>
<p>The apps I abandoned <strong>months ago</strong>?<br>
Sometimes, I <strong>go back</strong>, thinking,</p>
<p><em>&ldquo;Maybe they fixed it. Maybe it wasn’t so bad.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p>It was.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-windows-vs-iphone-struggle"><strong>The Windows vs. iPhone Struggle</strong></h2>
<p>If you’re an Apple user, you know that <strong>Apple apps just work together</strong>.<br>
But try finding an app that <strong>works flawlessly on both Windows and iPhone?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Good luck.</strong></p>
<p>I live in <strong>two worlds</strong>:</p>
<p>✔ <strong>Windows for work.</strong> It’s where I <strong>code, debug, and spend most of my day</strong>.<br>
✔ <strong>iPhone for personal life.</strong> It’s where I <strong>organize tasks, take notes, and communicate</strong>.</p>
<p>You’d think by now, in 2024, we’d have <strong>seamless cross-platform apps that work beautifully everywhere</strong>.</p>
<p>But no.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>iPhone apps</strong> are <strong>beautiful</strong>, but their <strong>Windows counterparts</strong> feel like <strong>afterthoughts</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>Windows apps</strong> are <strong>powerful</strong>, but most of them were <strong>designed by people who hate UI</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>The “cross-platform” apps?</strong> Usually the <strong>worst of both worlds</strong>.</li>
</ul>
<p>I thought switching to <strong>Android</strong> would solve this.</p>
<p>It didn’t.</p>
<p>It just gave me <strong>different</strong> problems.</p>
<p>I’ve even considered switching <strong>everything to Apple</strong>, but the thought of using <strong>macOS for development</strong> makes me break out in <strong>hives</strong>.<br>
I like my <strong>hardware customizable</strong> and my <strong>software open</strong>, thank you very much.</p>
<p>So I keep searching, hoping that <strong>one day, the perfect ecosystem will exist</strong>.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-inevitable-conclusion"><strong>The Inevitable Conclusion</strong></h2>
<p>At this point, I’ve <strong>accepted my fate</strong>.</p>
<p>I will <strong>never</strong> settle.</p>
<p>I will always <strong>tweak, test, uninstall, reinstall, and repeat</strong>.</p>
<ul>
<li>I will keep <strong>switching between One Commander and Total Commander</strong> because <strong>each is 90% perfect but missing one crucial feature</strong>.</li>
<li>I will keep <strong>trying every new calendar app</strong> that promises to <strong>revolutionize scheduling</strong>, only to <strong>go back to Google Calendar</strong>.</li>
<li>I will keep hoping that <strong>one day, Fantastical will magically become cross-platform</strong>.</li>
</ul>
<p>Maybe <strong>there is no perfect app</strong>.</p>
<p>Maybe the problem <strong>isn’t the apps—it’s me</strong>.</p>
<p>But until someone creates a:<br>
✔ <strong>Seamless</strong><br>
✔ <strong>Beautiful</strong><br>
✔ <strong>Feature-packed</strong><br>
✔ <strong>Cross-platform</strong><br>
✔ <strong>One-time-payment</strong><br>
✔ <strong>Ad-free</strong><br>
✔ <strong>Non-subscription</strong><br>
✔ <strong>Perfectly intuitive app for every function I need</strong>…</p>
<p>I’ll be here.<br>
<strong>Searching. Comparing. Complaining.</strong></p>
<p>And then <strong>downloading another one</strong>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Outsmart My Own Brain to Get Things Done</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-i-outsmart-my-brain-to-get-things-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-i-outsmart-my-brain-to-get-things-done/</guid>
      <description>Life feels like an action movie with no pause button. Here&amp;#39;s how I handle the chaos and still get things done.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My brain works like an <strong>action movie with no pause button</strong>. <strong>No clear story, no control</strong>, and just when things start to make sense—BAM! <strong>A sudden cut to something completely different.</strong></p>
<p>One moment, I’m focused, working hard. The next?</p>
<p>Oh wow, <strong>did you know ancient Romans made concrete</strong> that still exists today?<br>
Wait, wasn’t I supposed to answer an email?<br>
Oh, I should set a reminder for that. But which app? Maybe I should try a new one. Let me check&hellip;<br>
Wait. <strong>What was I doing?</strong></p>
<p>And just like that, 30 minutes disappear. I’m holding a coffee I don’t remember making, sitting in front of <strong>a completely different task</strong> than the one I started.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-productivity-toolbox-everything-i-tried-and-why-it-didnt-work"><strong>The Productivity Toolbox: Everything I Tried (and Why It Didn’t Work)</strong></h2>
<p>I’ve tested <strong>every productivity method</strong> I could find.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Post-it Notes?</strong> Great—until my desk looks like a detective’s crime board.</li>
<li><strong>Timers?</strong> Useful—if I remember I set them.</li>
<li><strong>To-do lists?</strong> I write them, I admire them&hellip; I never check them again.</li>
<li><strong>Productivity apps?</strong> I <strong>collect them like Pokémon.</strong> I have five for tasks, two for time tracking, and one for notes. But guess what? <strong>None work if I forget to open them.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Pomodoro?</strong> Nice idea—except I either ignore the timer or focus so much I forget time exists.</li>
</ul>
<p>I’ve heard all the usual advice:<br>
<em>&ldquo;Just choose your priorities!&rdquo;</em> But <strong>everything</strong> feels important.<br>
<em>&ldquo;Use reminders!&rdquo;</em> Great idea—if I remember to set them.<br>
<em>&ldquo;Have you tried digital planners?&rdquo;</em> Yes. I lost track of them too.</p>
<p>It’s not that I don’t try. I do. But <strong>my brain doesn’t follow the rules.</strong></p>
<p>And yet… <strong>I still get things done.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="how-i-actually-get-work-done"><strong>How I Actually Get Work Done</strong></h2>
<p>I stopped looking for <strong>one perfect system</strong>—because it doesn’t exist. Instead, I use a mix of <strong>simple tricks and mental hacks</strong> to keep myself productive.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>One task at a time.</strong> Multitasking? <strong>I quit that.</strong> If I try doing two things at once, I end up finishing <strong>nothing</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>Writing everything down.</strong> My memory is unreliable, so I put <strong>everything</strong> in Notion, on sticky notes, in alarms—anywhere my future self might find it.</li>
<li><strong>The Two-Minute Rule.</strong> If something takes <strong>less than two minutes</strong>, I do it <strong>right away</strong>. Otherwise, it disappears into <em>“I’ll do it later”</em> (which means never).</li>
<li><strong>Multiple timers.</strong> Since I forget I set a timer, I use <strong>two or three different ones</strong>. Sometimes, I even ask someone to remind me that I set a timer!</li>
<li><strong>Using my deep focus.</strong> When my brain decides something is <strong>THE MOST IMPORTANT TASK IN THE WORLD</strong>, I just go with it—even if it wasn’t planned.</li>
</ul>
<p>But the most important thing?</p>
<h3 id="i-work-with-my-brain-not-against-it"><strong>I Work With My Brain, Not Against It</strong></h3>
<p>I stopped trying to use <strong>systems made for other people</strong>. I can’t <strong>force</strong> focus, but I can <strong>catch it</strong> when it happens.</p>
<p>If I suddenly get <strong>super focused</strong> on a task, I don’t stop. If my brain jumps between ideas, I <strong>write them all down</strong> and organize them later.</p>
<p>My productivity is not <strong>straightforward</strong>. <strong>It moves in all directions.</strong> And that’s okay.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-tools-that-sometimes-help"><strong>The Tools That (Sometimes) Help</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Notion:</strong> My digital brain dump. If I don’t remember where I wrote something, it’s probably in Notion.</li>
<li><strong>Post-it Notes:</strong> Old-school but effective. I put them on my desk, my monitor, my wallet—everywhere.</li>
<li><strong>Timers (Lots of Them):</strong> On my phone, laptop, and smartwatch. <em>At least one might help me.</em></li>
<li><strong>Single-tasking mode:</strong> <strong>One window. One tab. One job.</strong> If I open a second tab, it means <strong>I need to do it later.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Solid Starts:</strong> Yes, even for feeding my son. Because <strong>focus problems don’t take a break</strong> when you’re a parent.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-takeaway"><strong>The Takeaway</strong></h2>
<p>Yes, my brain is <strong>chaotic</strong>. Yes, I sometimes open a new tab and forget why. Yes, I have <strong>a small collection of abandoned productivity tools</strong>.</p>
<p>But at the end of the day? <strong>I get things done.</strong></p>
<p>Not in a straight line. Not in a perfect way. But in <strong>my way.</strong></p>
<p>Because sometimes, <strong>thinking differently is what helps you find better solutions.</strong></p>
<p>So if you ever see me <strong>staring at the screen</strong>, just know:</p>
<ul>
<li>I might be solving a <strong>complicated problem</strong>&hellip;</li>
<li>&hellip;or I might have forgotten what I was doing.</li>
</ul>
<p>Either way, <strong>I’ll figure it out.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Browser Wars: My Exhausting Journey to Finding the Least Annoying Setup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/browser-wars-journey-to-least-annoying-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/browser-wars-journey-to-least-annoying-setup/</guid>
      <description>Choosing a browser shouldn&amp;#39;t be this hard. From Safari’s WebKit prison to Windows’ Chromium clones, here’s my exhausting browser journey.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m a software developer. I build things for the web. I write code.<br>
I understand how browsers work.</p>
<p>And yet, somehow, <strong>choosing a default browser nearly broke me.</strong></p>
<p>It wasn’t supposed to be this complicated. <strong>It’s just a browser.</strong><br>
A glorified <strong>tab holder</strong>. A tool to open Stack Overflow, forget why I opened it, and then open another tab instead.</p>
<p>But the moment I tried to pick <em>the one</em>—<strong>the browser that would rule them all</strong>—I descended into <strong>a personal crisis so deep I started questioning reality itself.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="round-1-the-iphone-problem-or-apples-webkit-prison"><strong>Round 1: The iPhone Problem (Or: Apple’s WebKit Prison)</strong></h2>
<p>I thought I had a choice.</p>
<p>I really did.</p>
<p>I believed I could just <strong>install Chrome or Firefox on my iPhone</strong> and live a normal life.</p>
<p>What a fool I was.</p>
<p>Because Apple, in its infinite wisdom, doesn’t actually let you <strong>use</strong> a real browser on iOS.<br>
No matter what I install—<strong>Chrome, Firefox, Brave, Edge, Vivaldi, Opera, or a browser hand-coded by an underground group of free software rebels</strong>—they’re <strong>all WebKit underneath.</strong></p>
<p>Which means every browser on iPhone is just <strong>Safari wearing a cheap disguise.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Chrome?</strong> Safari with Google Sync.</li>
<li><strong>Firefox?</strong> Safari with different branding.</li>
<li><strong>Brave?</strong> Safari with a tinfoil hat.</li>
</ul>
<p>There is no escape. Safari is the law.</p>
<p>I tried resisting. I tried using Chrome on my iPhone, <strong>convincing myself it was different.</strong><br>
It wasn’t.</p>
<p>The pages loaded the same. The bugs were the same.<br>
The only difference? <strong>A Google logo and more tracking.</strong></p>
<p>At some point, I accepted my fate. <strong>If everything is WebKit, I might as well use the original.</strong></p>
<p>Fine. <strong>Safari wins on iPhone.</strong><br>
Not because I love it, but because Apple made sure that fighting it would be a <strong>slow, battery-draining death.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="round-2-the-windows-browser-crisis-or-where-every-browser-is-the-same-anyway"><strong>Round 2: The Windows Browser Crisis (Or: Where Every Browser is the Same Anyway)</strong></h2>
<p>On Windows, the situation should be better. No WebKit dictatorship. No artificial restrictions. <strong>Freedom.</strong></p>
<p>Or so I thought.</p>
<p>In reality, <strong>every Windows browser is just Chromium with different personality issues.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Chrome</strong> – The original Chromium overlord. <strong>Fast, powerful, but eats RAM like it’s a competitive sport</strong> and makes you sign into a Google account just to exist.</li>
<li><strong>Brave</strong> – Chrome, but constantly reminding you that it’s better than Chrome. <strong>Also, why does it keep asking me about crypto?</strong></li>
<li><strong>Vivaldi</strong> – For people who think <strong>customizing a browser is a personality trait.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Opera</strong> – Who even uses Opera? Who are you people? <strong>Reveal yourselves.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Firefox</strong> – The only non-Chromium option, so I wanted to love it. <strong>But somehow, it makes every website feel slightly off</strong>, and the font rendering gives me trust issues.</li>
</ul>
<p>At this point, I realized something horrifying.</p>
<p><strong>Every time I tried a new browser, I ended up back in Chrome’s arms.</strong></p>
<p>Not because I <em>wanted</em> to, but because <strong>the entire web is optimized for Chromium.</strong></p>
<p>I wanted to love Firefox. I even tried convincing myself that <strong>the slightly-off fonts were a feature.</strong><br>
But in the end, it just made me feel like I was in an <strong>alternate universe where everything was almost right… but not quite.</strong></p>
<p>So, I gave up. If I had to use Chromium, I might as well use <strong>the version that’s optimized for Windows</strong> and doesn’t aggressively push Google services on me.</p>
<p>And that’s how <strong>Edge won by default.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="round-3-the-syncing-nightmare-or-how-i-glued-this-mess-together"><strong>Round 3: The Syncing Nightmare (Or: How I Glued This Mess Together)</strong></h2>
<p>So now I had:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Safari on iPhone</strong> (<em>because Apple won’t let me have nice things</em>).</li>
<li><strong>Edge on Windows</strong> (<em>because all Chromium browsers are the same, and Edge just integrates better</em>).</li>
</ul>
<p>But now came the <strong>real</strong> problem.</p>
<p><strong>How do I sync bookmarks between two browsers that don’t want to talk to each other?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Google wants me to <strong>use Chrome on everything</strong> like some kind of cross-platform cult.</li>
<li>Apple wants me to <strong>use Safari on everything</strong> because I made the mistake of owning an iPhone.</li>
<li>Microsoft wants me to <strong>embrace Edge fully</strong> and probably switch to Bing while I’m at it.</li>
</ul>
<p>I refused to let any of them win.</p>
<p>So I <strong>hacked my way out</strong> with <strong>iCloud Bookmarks Extension for Edge.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Now <strong>Safari and Edge share bookmarks</strong> like two kids forced to get along.</li>
<li>I don’t need Google.</li>
<li>I don’t need third-party syncing tools.</li>
<li>And best of all, <strong>I can finally stop switching browsers every two weeks.</strong></li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="final-thoughts-the-browser-wars-were-a-lie"><strong>Final Thoughts: The Browser Wars Were a Lie</strong></h2>
<p>After all this research, testing, and <strong>questioning my life choices</strong>, I have one conclusion:</p>
<p><strong>All browsers are terrible.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Some track you aggressively.</li>
<li>Some drain your battery.</li>
<li>Some crash randomly.</li>
<li>Some make you feel guilty for using them.</li>
</ul>
<p>But in the end? <strong>A browser is just a tool.</strong></p>
<p>The best one is <strong>the one that gets in your way the least.</strong></p>
<p>For me, that means:</p>
<p>✔ <strong>Safari on iPhone</strong> (<em>because fighting Apple is exhausting</em>).<br>
✔ <strong>Edge on Windows</strong> (<em>because if all Chromium browsers are the same, I might as well pick the one with better Windows integration</em>).<br>
✔ <strong>iCloud Sync</strong> (<em>because I refuse to let Google own my bookmarks</em>).</p>
<p>Is it perfect? No.<br>
Is it better than switching browsers every week? <strong>Yes.</strong><br>
Will I probably change my mind in six months? <strong>Also yes.</strong></p>
<p>Because let’s be real—<strong>the moment you finally settle on a setup, something new comes along to break everything.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
