<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Exhaustion on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/exhaustion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Exhaustion on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.144.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/exhaustion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why You’re Always Tired (And It’s Not Just About Sleep)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-youre-always-tired-not-just-about-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-youre-always-tired-not-just-about-sleep/</guid>
      <description>Tired all the time? It’s not just about sleep. Discover the 5 types of exhaustion and how to truly recharge.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="why-youre-always-tired-and-its-not-just-about-sleep"><strong>Why You’re Always Tired (And It’s Not Just About Sleep)</strong></h1>
<p>For the longest time, I thought I was just <em>tired.</em></p>
<p>Not enough sleep, too much work, a 9-month-old who thinks 3 AM is party time. Classic exhaustion, right?</p>
<p>So I did what everyone does: chugged coffee, tried to sleep more, and powered through.</p>
<p>But no matter what I did, the fatigue <strong>never went away.</strong></p>
<p>I blamed it on parenthood. On work. On stress. I figured, <em>&ldquo;This is just adulthood. Everyone is tired.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p>Then I realized something.</p>
<p>I wasn’t just <strong>physically</strong> exhausted. I was mentally overloaded, emotionally drained, creatively empty.</p>
<p>And no amount of caffeine or extra sleep could fix it.</p>
<p>Because <strong>we don’t just have one type of energy—so we don’t just get tired in one way.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-5-types-of-exhaustion-and-why-we-ignore-them"><strong>The 5 Types of Exhaustion (And Why We Ignore Them)</strong></h2>
<h3 id="1-mental-exhaustion-the-overloaded-brain"><strong>1. Mental Exhaustion</strong> (<em>The Overloaded Brain</em>)</h3>
<p>Too many tabs open (in your browser <em>and</em> your head). Constant context-switching. Information overload. You sit down to work and suddenly forget what you were supposed to do.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Symptoms:</strong> Brain fog, forgetfulness, inability to focus, procrastination.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="2-emotional-exhaustion-the-feeling-drain"><strong>2. Emotional Exhaustion</strong> (<em>The Feeling Drain</em>)</h3>
<p>When your emotions are on overdrive—too many decisions, too many worries, too much social pressure. Even small conversations feel like heavy lifting.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Symptoms:</strong> Irritability, feeling overwhelmed, emotional numbness, quick to snap.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="3-creative-exhaustion-the-empty-tank"><strong>3. Creative Exhaustion</strong> (<em>The Empty Tank</em>)</h3>
<p>The silent killer of inspiration. When your brain has been in &lsquo;output mode&rsquo; for too long without enough input. You stare at a blank screen, and your best idea is… nothing.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Symptoms:</strong> Writer’s block, lack of ideas, feeling uninspired, repetitive thinking.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="4-social-exhaustion-the-people-drain"><strong>4. Social Exhaustion</strong> (<em>The People Drain</em>)</h3>
<p>It’s not about being an introvert or extrovert—it’s about too much social interaction (or the wrong kind). Even replying to a text feels like a chore.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Symptoms:</strong> Social avoidance, feeling drained after interactions, irritability in social settings.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="5-sensory-exhaustion-the-overstimulation-overload"><strong>5. Sensory Exhaustion</strong> (<em>The Overstimulation Overload</em>)</h3>
<p>Noise, notifications, screens, flashing lights. Your brain is constantly processing micro-stimuli, and it <strong>never shuts up.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Symptoms:</strong> Feeling agitated by noise, craving silence, overstimulation, physical restlessness.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="why-we-stay-exhausted-even-when-we-rest"><strong>Why We Stay Exhausted (Even When We Rest)</strong></h2>
<p>Here’s the problem: <strong>we treat them all the same way.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Mental exhaustion?</strong> We take a break—but then scroll through social media, keeping our brain in overdrive.</li>
<li><strong>Emotional exhaustion?</strong> We binge-watch Netflix, numbing our feelings instead of processing them.</li>
<li><strong>Creative exhaustion?</strong> We try to push through, thinking more effort will fix it.</li>
<li><strong>Social exhaustion?</strong> We go to more events, mistaking loneliness for social fatigue.</li>
<li><strong>Sensory exhaustion?</strong> We &ldquo;relax&rdquo; by staring at another screen.</li>
</ul>
<p>We assume a nap, a Netflix binge, or a “day off” will fix it.</p>
<p>But if you don’t know <em>what kind</em> of tired you are, you’ll never recover properly.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="so-heres-how-im-fixing-it"><strong>So Here’s How I’m Fixing It</strong></h2>
<p>Instead of &ldquo;resting&rdquo; in a generic way, I’m <strong>resting with purpose.</strong></p>
<p>I match the type of rest to the type of exhaustion I’m feeling.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="1-mental-exhaustion--give-your-brain-a-reset"><strong>1. Mental Exhaustion → Give Your Brain a Reset</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Deep work in short bursts</strong> – Focused sessions (like 25-minute Pomodoros) to reduce context-switching.</li>
<li><strong>Digital decluttering</strong> – Fewer tabs, fewer notifications, no mindless scrolling.</li>
<li><strong>Brain dump journaling</strong> – Writing down every stray thought to clear mental space.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="2-emotional-exhaustion--reduce-decision-fatigue"><strong>2. Emotional Exhaustion → Reduce Decision Fatigue</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Fewer choices</strong> – I pre-plan meals, outfits, and small decisions so my brain doesn’t have to.</li>
<li><strong>Emotional boundaries</strong> – Saying ‘no’ more often and limiting draining interactions.</li>
<li><strong>Journaling</strong> – Processing emotions by writing them out instead of bottling them up.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="3-creative-exhaustion--refuel-your-inspiration"><strong>3. Creative Exhaustion → Refuel Your Inspiration</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Consume good input</strong> – Reading, watching inspiring videos, experiencing new things.</li>
<li><strong>Change of scenery</strong> – Walking, visiting a new place, or simply switching rooms to reset my perspective.</li>
<li><strong>Play</strong> – Doing something fun and unrelated to work, like sketching or playing with my kids.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="4-social-exhaustion--intentional-solitude"><strong>4. Social Exhaustion → Intentional Solitude</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Meaningful connections only</strong> – Prioritizing deep conversations over small talk.</li>
<li><strong>Scheduled alone time</strong> – Planning solo moments to recharge without interruptions.</li>
<li><strong>Boundaries</strong> – Limiting social commitments and giving myself permission to cancel.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="5-sensory-exhaustion--turn-down-the-noise"><strong>5. Sensory Exhaustion → Turn Down the Noise</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Digital detox</strong> – No screens before bed. Phone on silent or Do Not Disturb mode.</li>
<li><strong>Minimalist workspace</strong> – Reducing visual clutter to minimize sensory overload.</li>
<li><strong>Silence and darkness</strong> – Spending time in quiet, dark environments to reset my senses.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-takeaway"><strong>The Takeaway</strong></h2>
<p>We’ve been tricked into thinking exhaustion is just about <em>not sleeping enough.</em></p>
<p>But the real question isn’t <strong>&ldquo;Am I tired?&rdquo;</strong>—it’s <strong>&ldquo;What kind of tired am I?&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p>Once you figure that out?<br>
You can finally start <strong>recharging the right way.</strong></p>
<p>And you might just find that you’re not broken.<br>
You were just <strong>resting wrong.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
