<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Critical Thinking on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/critical-thinking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Critical Thinking on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.144.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/critical-thinking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Changing Your Mind is a Sign of Intelligence, Not Weakness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-changing-your-mind-is-a-sign-of-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-changing-your-mind-is-a-sign-of-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>Changing your mind isn’t a weakness—it’s growth. Discover why evolving your perspective makes you smarter and more adaptable.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some people think <strong>changing your mind is a weakness</strong>—that once you take a stance, you have to defend it forever. That <strong>certainty equals strength</strong> and doubt makes you unreliable.</p>
<p>I <strong>completely disagree.</strong></p>
<p>I change my mind <strong>all the time.</strong> Not because I’m indecisive, but because <strong>I’m learning.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-art-of-arguing-with-yourself"><strong>The Art of Arguing With Yourself</strong></h2>
<p>It’s easy to believe your opinion is right. After all, <strong>your brain worked hard to form it.</strong></p>
<p>And then, suddenly&hellip; doubt creeps in.</p>
<p>You start thinking about the <strong>opposite perspective.</strong> You challenge your own logic. You realize, <em>maybe I was missing something.</em></p>
<p>Some people panic when this happens. They think it means they were wrong. They feel embarrassed. Defensive. But I see it differently: <strong>every time I change my mind, I get closer to the truth.</strong></p>
<p>I’ve realized that my opinions are just <strong>snapshots</strong> of what I understood at the time. And like outdated software, they need <strong>updates.</strong></p>
<p>I constantly ask myself:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>What if I’m wrong?</em></li>
<li><em>What am I not considering?</em></li>
<li><em>How would someone who disagrees with me see this?</em></li>
</ul>
<p>I argue <strong>against my own beliefs</strong> to test their strength. I look for <strong>holes in my logic.</strong></p>
<p>This isn’t being indecisive. <strong>This is debugging my own thinking.</strong></p>
<p>And every time I find a flaw, I fix it. <strong>I upgrade.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="marriage-the-ultimate-debate-club"><strong>Marriage: The Ultimate Debate Club</strong></h2>
<p>If you want practice in <strong>changing your mind</strong>, get married.</p>
<p>My wife and I <strong>love</strong> to debate. Not argue—debate.</p>
<p>It starts with small things:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Is this really the best way to load the dishwasher?</em></li>
<li><em>Is a hot dog a sandwich?</em></li>
<li><em>Do we really need to rearrange the furniture again?</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Then, two hours later, we’re deep into <strong>life, philosophy, and the meaning of everything.</strong></p>
<p>And sometimes, <strong>we completely switch sides.</strong></p>
<p>Not because one of us &ldquo;won.&rdquo;<br>
Not because we’re trying to be &ldquo;right.&rdquo;</p>
<p>But because we actually <strong>listened</strong> to each other.</p>
<p>Because <strong>seeing the world through someone else’s eyes makes you smarter.</strong></p>
<p>And yes, sometimes, she’s right, and I have to admit I was wrong.<br>
(Okay, <strong>often</strong> she’s right, but that’s another story.)</p>
<p>But every time I admit I was wrong, <strong>I get smarter.</strong><br>
And every time she does, <strong>we both grow.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="why-changing-your-mind-is-a-superpower"><strong>Why Changing Your Mind is a Superpower</strong></h2>
<p>Here’s what I’ve learned:</p>
<ul>
<li>If you never change your mind, <strong>you’re not learning.</strong> You’re just repeating yourself.</li>
<li>Admitting you were wrong <strong>doesn’t make you weak.</strong> It makes you someone people actually trust.</li>
<li>The smartest people <strong>aren’t the ones who refuse to budge.</strong> They’re the ones who keep refining their ideas.</li>
</ul>
<p>Think about it:</p>
<p>Every time you change your mind, it means <strong>you’ve learned something new.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Science evolves</strong> by questioning and updating its ideas.</li>
<li><strong>Great leaders</strong> adjust their strategies when new information comes in.</li>
<li><strong>Successful people</strong> don’t fear being wrong—they use it as a chance to grow.</li>
</ul>
<p>Changing your mind <strong>doesn’t mean you were stupid before.</strong><br>
It means you’re <strong>smarter now.</strong></p>
<p>It doesn’t mean you were wrong.<br>
It means <strong>you’ve improved.</strong></p>
<p>And over time? Your thinking gets closer and closer to something that actually resembles <strong>the truth.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="version-20-and-beyond"><strong>Version 2.0 (And Beyond)</strong></h2>
<p>I used to think that changing my mind meant I was inconsistent.<br>
Now, I see it as <strong>a sign of growth.</strong></p>
<p>I don’t want to be <strong>version 1.0 of myself forever.</strong><br>
I want to be <strong>2.0, 3.0, 10.0</strong>—constantly upgrading, constantly improving.</p>
<p>Some people are <strong>proud of being &ldquo;consistent.&rdquo;</strong> But if you’re consistent <strong>just for the sake of consistency</strong>, you’re not growing—you’re stuck.</p>
<p>People who never change their minds? <strong>They’re frozen in time.</strong><br>
People who adapt, question, and rethink? <strong>They’re evolving.</strong></p>
<p>And that means being willing to say,<br>
<em>&ldquo;I was wrong.&rdquo;</em><br>
<em>&ldquo;I learned something new.&rdquo;</em><br>
<em>&ldquo;I’ve updated my thinking.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p>It means embracing <strong>doubt, curiosity, and growth.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-takeaway"><strong>The Takeaway</strong></h2>
<p>People think strength is about <strong>sticking to your guns no matter what.</strong><br>
But real strength? <strong>Real strength is knowing when to change your mind.</strong></p>
<p>It’s about:</p>
<ul>
<li>Being <strong>curious</strong> enough to question yourself.</li>
<li>Being <strong>humble</strong> enough to admit when you’re wrong.</li>
<li>Being <strong>smart</strong> enough to see doubt as a tool for growth.</li>
</ul>
<p>So the next time someone accuses you of <strong>flip-flopping</strong>, don’t take it as an insult.<br>
Take it as <strong>proof that you’re evolving.</strong></p>
<p>Because the strongest minds?<br>
They’re the ones that <strong>never stop upgrading.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
