<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Life Lessons on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/life-lessons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life Lessons on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.144.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/life-lessons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I Never Thought I’d Grow a Beard (But Here We Are)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-never-thought-id-grow-a-beard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-never-thought-id-grow-a-beard/</guid>
      <description>Growing a beard was never in my plans. But this accidental experiment taught me more about identity than I expected.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve never been a <strong>beard guy.</strong></p>
<p>For most of my life, I thought of facial hair as something that just <strong>happened</strong> to other people—like an automatic feature that unlocked at a certain age. I’d see guys with <strong>thick, full beards</strong> and think, <em>Yeah, that’s just not for me.</em></p>
<p>It wasn’t even a conscious decision. It was more like an unspoken agreement with myself:</p>
<p>✔ <strong>I shave because I always have.</strong><br>
✔ <strong>I’m just not a beard person.</strong></p>
<p>And then, one day&hellip; <strong>I didn’t shave.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-accidental-beard-experiment"><strong>The Accidental Beard Experiment</strong></h2>
<p>I didn’t wake up one morning and decide, <em>I shall grow a beard!</em></p>
<p>It started with a few skipped shaves. Life got busy. I got lazy. And before I knew it, my face had <strong>more stubble than usual.</strong></p>
<p>Normally, this would have <strong>annoyed me.</strong> But this time?</p>
<p>I let it stay.</p>
<p>At first, it felt weird—like my <strong>own face was betraying me.</strong> I&rsquo;d catch glimpses of myself and think, <em>Who is this guy?</em></p>
<p>The <strong>itchy phase</strong> was real.<br>
The <strong>awkward patchy phase</strong> was even more real.</p>
<p>But the strangest part?</p>
<p>I <strong>kind of liked it.</strong></p>
<p>I started noticing little things:</p>
<ul>
<li>It made me <strong>look older</strong> (or maybe just <em>different</em>).</li>
<li>It <strong>changed the shape of my face.</strong></li>
<li>I kept catching myself <strong>stroking my chin like some kind of wise philosopher.</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>And the itch? It wasn’t as bad as I thought. More like a <strong>reminder</strong> that something was changing.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="why-growing-a-beard-felt-so-different"><strong>Why Growing a Beard Felt So… Different</strong></h2>
<p>It’s funny how something as simple as <strong>not shaving</strong> can change the way you see yourself.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>I looked different.</strong> My face had more definition. My jawline felt stronger. It was like a <strong>real-life Instagram filter.</strong></li>
<li><strong>I felt different.</strong> There was something about it—maybe confidence, maybe curiosity—that made me feel more <strong>deliberate.</strong> Like I had <em>made a choice</em>, even if that choice was just to&hellip; not shave.</li>
<li><strong>Other people noticed.</strong>
<ul>
<li><em>&ldquo;Oh, you’re growing it out?&rdquo;</em></li>
<li><em>&ldquo;Hey, that actually suits you.&rdquo;</em></li>
<li><em>&ldquo;You look… more Italian now.&rdquo;</em> (<em>That one made me laugh.</em>)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I wasn’t prepared for how much <strong>other people</strong> would comment on it. It was like I had <strong>changed something huge</strong>, when all I did was&hellip; <em>nothing.</em></p>
<p>And every time someone mentioned it, I felt this weird mix of <strong>pride and discomfort.</strong> Like I was being <strong>seen in a new way</strong>—and I wasn’t sure how I felt about that.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="what-i-learned-from-letting-my-face-do-its-thing"><strong>What I Learned From Letting My Face Do Its Thing</strong></h2>
<p>Growing a beard <strong>didn’t change my life.</strong></p>
<p>But it did make me <strong>realize something important.</strong></p>
<p>So many of the things we believe about ourselves—our <strong>“defaults”</strong>—aren’t actually rules. They’re just <strong>habits.</strong></p>
<p>For years, I thought:<br>
✔ <em>I’m a clean-shaven guy.</em><br>
✔ <em>Beards don’t suit me.</em><br>
✔ <em>This is just how I look.</em></p>
<p>And then, in a matter of weeks, those “truths” <strong>disappeared.</strong></p>
<p>It made me wonder:<br>
<em>How many other things do I believe about myself just because they’ve always been that way?</em></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>I’m not a morning person.</strong> (<em>Or am I just used to staying up late?</em>)</li>
<li><strong>I don’t like public speaking.</strong> (<em>Or have I just never given it a real chance?</em>)</li>
<li><strong>I’m not a beard guy.</strong> (<em>Or did I just never let it grow long enough to find out?</em>)</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s strange how something as simple as <strong>not shaving</strong> can make you question so much more.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="will-i-keep-it"><strong>Will I Keep It?</strong></h2>
<p>I don’t know yet. Maybe I’ll <strong>shave it off next week.</strong><br>
Maybe I’ll <strong>keep it longer.</strong></p>
<p>Right now, I’m just <strong>letting it be.</strong></p>
<p>No expectations. No rules. Just <strong>curiosity.</strong></p>
<p>But either way, this isn’t really about the beard.</p>
<p>It’s about realizing that sometimes, <strong>the smallest change can make you see yourself in a whole new way.</strong></p>
<p>And honestly? <strong>That’s worth exploring.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why We Romanticize the Past (And Why It Keeps Us Stuck)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-we-romanticize-the-past-and-why-its-a-trap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-we-romanticize-the-past-and-why-its-a-trap/</guid>
      <description>We often think the past was better, but nostalgia tricks us. Discover why we romanticize the past and how to appreciate the present.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="why-we-romanticize-the-past-and-why-it-keeps-us-stuck"><strong>Why We Romanticize the Past (And Why It Keeps Us Stuck)</strong></h1>
<p>Ever caught yourself thinking, <em>“Things were better back then”</em>?</p>
<p>Maybe it’s childhood summers that seemed endless, music that just <em>felt</em> different, or the way life seemed simpler before everything became digital, fast, and exhausting.</p>
<p>I do this all the time.</p>
<p>I think about my years in Italy—the long walks, the fresh bread from the corner bakery, the feeling of time stretching endlessly.<br>
I remember the early days of the internet, when everything felt new, when logging off actually meant being <em>disconnected.</em></p>
<p>And then, reality hits me: <strong>the past wasn’t actually better. It just feels that way.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-nostalgia-filter-why-we-rewrite-our-own-history"><strong>The Nostalgia Filter: Why We Rewrite Our Own History</strong></h2>
<p>Our brains don’t store memories like a hard drive. They <strong>edit, distort, and reshape</strong> them over time. And they’re <em>really</em> good at two things:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Blurring the bad parts.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>We naturally forget the stress, the boredom, the awkward moments.</li>
<li>The brain smooths out the rough edges, leaving behind a highlight reel.</li>
<li>It’s why vacations seem perfect in hindsight—even though we spent half the time arguing over directions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Intensifying emotions.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Our best memories aren’t just stored; they’re amplified.</li>
<li>The sunsets were warmer, the music hit harder, and even the smallest moments felt <em>magical.</em></li>
<li>We remember how we <em>felt</em>, not necessarily how things <em>were.</em></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<p>This is why childhood feels dreamlike, why first loves seem impossible to recreate, and why people always say, <em>“They don’t make movies like they used to.”</em></p>
<p>It’s not that things were better. <strong>It’s that we experienced them differently.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="why-we-crave-the-past-and-how-it-tricks-us"><strong>Why We Crave the Past (And How It Tricks Us)</strong></h2>
<p>So why do we keep looking back?</p>
<p>Because nostalgia is <strong>a safe place</strong>—one where we already know how everything turns out.</p>
<p>And when the present feels overwhelming? Our brains do something sneaky:</p>
<p>They make the past feel <strong>simpler, warmer, and more certain</strong> than it actually was.</p>
<p>Think about it:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>The ‘90s?</strong><br>
We remember the cartoons, not the dial-up internet and expensive long-distance calls.</li>
<li><strong>Childhood?</strong><br>
We remember the carefree summers, not the school stress and wanting to grow up faster.</li>
<li><strong>Early relationships?</strong><br>
We remember the butterflies, not the heartbreaks and confusion.</li>
</ul>
<p>I romanticize my years in Italy. I remember the sunsets over the Adriatic Sea, the long dinners, the laughter echoing in the streets.<br>
But I conveniently forget the struggles: the homesickness, the financial stress, the feeling of being an outsider.</p>
<p>My brain <strong>edited those parts out.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-double-edged-sword-of-nostalgia"><strong>The Double-Edged Sword of Nostalgia</strong></h2>
<p>Nostalgia isn’t inherently bad. It can be <strong>beautiful, comforting, and inspiring.</strong><br>
But it becomes dangerous when we start believing the edited version over the real one.</p>
<p>When we convince ourselves that the past was better, we <strong>rob the present of its potential.</strong></p>
<p>We start thinking:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>“Things will never be as good as they were.”</em></li>
<li><em>“I was happier back then.”</em></li>
<li><em>“The world is worse now.”</em></li>
</ul>
<p>But was it really better?<br>
Or did we just experience it <strong>differently</strong>?</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="so"><strong>So&hellip; Should We Stop Romanticizing the Past?</strong></h2>
<p>Not at all. Nostalgia is <strong>a tool, not a trap—if we use it the right way.</strong></p>
<p>Here’s how I see it now:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Instead of chasing the past, I use it as a guide.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>What made those times feel special?</li>
<li>Was it the slower pace? The deep conversations? The sense of adventure?</li>
<li>Maybe I need <em>more</em> of that in my life today.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Instead of seeing the past as “better,” I see it as a different chapter.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Every stage of life has its own kind of magic—I just have to notice it.</li>
<li>If childhood was about wonder and discovery, maybe adulthood is about <strong>creation and purpose.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Instead of comparing, I create.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The past didn’t have some secret ingredient that’s missing today.</li>
<li>The magic isn’t gone—it’s just waiting for me to make it again.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-takeaway"><strong>The Takeaway</strong></h2>
<p>Nostalgia isn’t a doorway back in time. It’s a <strong>mirror</strong>—one that shows us what we love, what we miss, and what we need to bring into the present.</p>
<p>It’s a reminder that the magic we felt back then didn’t come from the world being better.<br>
It came from <strong>how we experienced it.</strong></p>
<p>We were present. We were curious. We were open to wonder.</p>
<p>So next time you find yourself saying, <em>“Things were better back then”</em>, stop and ask:</p>
<p><em>Or maybe&hellip; I was just better at living in the moment?</em></p>
<p>Maybe the problem isn’t with today. Maybe it’s with how <strong>distracted, rushed, and stressed</strong> we’ve become.</p>
<p>Maybe the best days aren’t behind us.<br>
<strong>Maybe they’re just waiting to be noticed.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
