<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mental Strategies on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/mental-strategies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mental Strategies on Dominic&#39;s Sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.144.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/mental-strategies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How I Outsmart My Own Brain to Get Things Done</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-i-outsmart-my-brain-to-get-things-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-i-outsmart-my-brain-to-get-things-done/</guid>
      <description>Life feels like an action movie with no pause button. Here&amp;#39;s how I handle the chaos and still get things done.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My brain works like an <strong>action movie with no pause button</strong>. <strong>No clear story, no control</strong>, and just when things start to make sense—BAM! <strong>A sudden cut to something completely different.</strong></p>
<p>One moment, I’m focused, working hard. The next?</p>
<p>Oh wow, <strong>did you know ancient Romans made concrete</strong> that still exists today?<br>
Wait, wasn’t I supposed to answer an email?<br>
Oh, I should set a reminder for that. But which app? Maybe I should try a new one. Let me check&hellip;<br>
Wait. <strong>What was I doing?</strong></p>
<p>And just like that, 30 minutes disappear. I’m holding a coffee I don’t remember making, sitting in front of <strong>a completely different task</strong> than the one I started.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-productivity-toolbox-everything-i-tried-and-why-it-didnt-work"><strong>The Productivity Toolbox: Everything I Tried (and Why It Didn’t Work)</strong></h2>
<p>I’ve tested <strong>every productivity method</strong> I could find.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Post-it Notes?</strong> Great—until my desk looks like a detective’s crime board.</li>
<li><strong>Timers?</strong> Useful—if I remember I set them.</li>
<li><strong>To-do lists?</strong> I write them, I admire them&hellip; I never check them again.</li>
<li><strong>Productivity apps?</strong> I <strong>collect them like Pokémon.</strong> I have five for tasks, two for time tracking, and one for notes. But guess what? <strong>None work if I forget to open them.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Pomodoro?</strong> Nice idea—except I either ignore the timer or focus so much I forget time exists.</li>
</ul>
<p>I’ve heard all the usual advice:<br>
<em>&ldquo;Just choose your priorities!&rdquo;</em> But <strong>everything</strong> feels important.<br>
<em>&ldquo;Use reminders!&rdquo;</em> Great idea—if I remember to set them.<br>
<em>&ldquo;Have you tried digital planners?&rdquo;</em> Yes. I lost track of them too.</p>
<p>It’s not that I don’t try. I do. But <strong>my brain doesn’t follow the rules.</strong></p>
<p>And yet… <strong>I still get things done.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="how-i-actually-get-work-done"><strong>How I Actually Get Work Done</strong></h2>
<p>I stopped looking for <strong>one perfect system</strong>—because it doesn’t exist. Instead, I use a mix of <strong>simple tricks and mental hacks</strong> to keep myself productive.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>One task at a time.</strong> Multitasking? <strong>I quit that.</strong> If I try doing two things at once, I end up finishing <strong>nothing</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>Writing everything down.</strong> My memory is unreliable, so I put <strong>everything</strong> in Notion, on sticky notes, in alarms—anywhere my future self might find it.</li>
<li><strong>The Two-Minute Rule.</strong> If something takes <strong>less than two minutes</strong>, I do it <strong>right away</strong>. Otherwise, it disappears into <em>“I’ll do it later”</em> (which means never).</li>
<li><strong>Multiple timers.</strong> Since I forget I set a timer, I use <strong>two or three different ones</strong>. Sometimes, I even ask someone to remind me that I set a timer!</li>
<li><strong>Using my deep focus.</strong> When my brain decides something is <strong>THE MOST IMPORTANT TASK IN THE WORLD</strong>, I just go with it—even if it wasn’t planned.</li>
</ul>
<p>But the most important thing?</p>
<h3 id="i-work-with-my-brain-not-against-it"><strong>I Work With My Brain, Not Against It</strong></h3>
<p>I stopped trying to use <strong>systems made for other people</strong>. I can’t <strong>force</strong> focus, but I can <strong>catch it</strong> when it happens.</p>
<p>If I suddenly get <strong>super focused</strong> on a task, I don’t stop. If my brain jumps between ideas, I <strong>write them all down</strong> and organize them later.</p>
<p>My productivity is not <strong>straightforward</strong>. <strong>It moves in all directions.</strong> And that’s okay.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-tools-that-sometimes-help"><strong>The Tools That (Sometimes) Help</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Notion:</strong> My digital brain dump. If I don’t remember where I wrote something, it’s probably in Notion.</li>
<li><strong>Post-it Notes:</strong> Old-school but effective. I put them on my desk, my monitor, my wallet—everywhere.</li>
<li><strong>Timers (Lots of Them):</strong> On my phone, laptop, and smartwatch. <em>At least one might help me.</em></li>
<li><strong>Single-tasking mode:</strong> <strong>One window. One tab. One job.</strong> If I open a second tab, it means <strong>I need to do it later.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Solid Starts:</strong> Yes, even for feeding my son. Because <strong>focus problems don’t take a break</strong> when you’re a parent.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-takeaway"><strong>The Takeaway</strong></h2>
<p>Yes, my brain is <strong>chaotic</strong>. Yes, I sometimes open a new tab and forget why. Yes, I have <strong>a small collection of abandoned productivity tools</strong>.</p>
<p>But at the end of the day? <strong>I get things done.</strong></p>
<p>Not in a straight line. Not in a perfect way. But in <strong>my way.</strong></p>
<p>Because sometimes, <strong>thinking differently is what helps you find better solutions.</strong></p>
<p>So if you ever see me <strong>staring at the screen</strong>, just know:</p>
<ul>
<li>I might be solving a <strong>complicated problem</strong>&hellip;</li>
<li>&hellip;or I might have forgotten what I was doing.</li>
</ul>
<p>Either way, <strong>I’ll figure it out.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
